Logan Thomas

Senior Associate Data Scientist I

Born 1989 in Mountain View, CA





Experience

Senior Associate Data Scientist I

Protection Engineering Consultants Austin, TX Aug 2019 - Present Advanced Technology & Research Team

Course Instructor

DataCamp Remote Feb 2019 - Present

Lead Data Scientist

Nielsen Austin, TX Oct 2018 - Aug 2019 Machine Learning & Algorithms Team

Senior Data Scientist

Nielsen San Francisco, CA Aug 2016 - Oct 2018 **Digital Product Team**

Applied Analytics Program Associate - School of **Professional Studies**

Columbia University Remote Sep 2016 - Dec 2016 Course Facilitator - Applied Analytics in an Organizational Context

Data Scientist

Nielsen Tampa, FL & San Francisco, CA July 2014 - Aug 2016 **Emerging Leaders Program**



Education

University of Florida

Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering 2012 - 2014 Minor in Statistics

Palm Beach Atlantic University

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics 2008 - 2012 Minor in Biblical Studies; Graduated Summa Cum Laude

Projects

turkey-bowl **Python** Thanksgiving tradition -Mock NFL fantasy

football draft.

repo-scrape Python GitHub metadata scraping (Hacktoberfest).

python-practice **Python** Collection of personal Python notes, challenges, and scripts.



Contributions

pyjanitor Pythonic API for elegant data cleaning and method Algorithms in Python. chaining routines on pandas DataFrames.

deap Distributed Evolutionary

pint

Python package to define, operate and manipulate physical quantities - the product of a numerical

About me

I'm a highly motivated and naturally curious individual with 6 years of experience using data science & machine learning techniques. I exhibit an analytical and detail-oriented nature, while placing strong value on building relationships.

Skills



Contact



✓ logan.thomas005@gmail.com

(321) 961-9107

in logan-thomas

loganthomas